JOE: There are many charities,
organisations and community
support groups who work to
support the needs of individuals
with autism and their families.
They may be involved in purely providing
support, guidance and advice or may be
involved in campaigning for improved
rights, services and opportunities
like the ‘National Autistic Society’.
BETH: It doesn’t matter how big or small
the organisation or group is, their main
aim is usually to help to create a better
functioning society for individuals
with autism and their families.
JOE: Autism charities can offer a
large amount of information on their
sites, with links to other charities
support agencies and online forums.
Some even have directories giving
lists of services available.
The ‘NHS’ website itself
has a lot of information and
links to other organisations.
BETH: Social media such as ‘twitter’
and ‘facebook’ can help give links
to information for many different
kinds of support, along with personal
advice and event information.
Often charities will have their
own facebook page or twitter feed.
JOE: There are many people with experience
of autism offering support and sharing
their stories on forums and social media.
It’s not always necessary to talk to
others in online groups, but reading or
hearing about other people's experiences,
can help make it easier to understand some
of the problems, and how they may relate.
BETH: Comments on social media are
often based on personal experience of
individuals and families and should
be taken in the context in which
they are written, and not as advice
that will help someone directly.
Also, any information on the internet,
unless it’s from a registered or
official source, should always be
double checked and cross referenced,
to make sure that it is correct and
supported by the appropriate authorities.
JOE: Local councils can help
with advice and support and
maybe able to organise financial
benefits, depending on situation.
For children and young people under
25 councils have a ‘local offer’
which is support for young people
with special educational needs.
For adults with autism or parents
and carers, a council can do a
‘needs’ assessment or a ‘carers’
assessment to find out what problems
there are, and if any support or
financial benefits might be available.
BETH: Some people might be wary of
the internet or about letting people
know their situation, but there
is a lot of information, help and
support available online or by phone.
Also support doesn’t always have
to be given online, once links are
established, face to face support
can develop, if this preferred.